"Twentieth Century Trade Union Women: Vehicle for Social Change" Oral History Transcripts 6342 OHT
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
"Twentieth Century Trade Union Women: Vehicle for Social Change" Oral History Transcripts
1970-1987
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations (University of Illinois)
University of Michigan
6342 OHT
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Oral histories.
7735919
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 20, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 27, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Balanoff, Elizabeth; Barron, Sara; Bernhardt, Debra; Bowie, Carol; Callahan, Mary; Cameron, Cindia; Cobble, Susan; Cohen, Sophie; Conroy, Catherine; Craig, Bette; Day, Clara; Dubrow, Evelyn; Elkuss, Mary Lawrance; Fese, Marie; Findlay, James; Julik, Gary; Simmons, Christian; Smith, Judy; Frank, Mary Ellen; Frederickson, Mary; Fredgant, Sara; Gladstein, Caroline Decker; Goldfarb, Lyn; Goldfarb, Lyn; Kliener, Lydia; Miller, Christine; Gordon, Gloria; Haener, Dorothy; Hall, Jacquelyn; Herstein, Lillian; Hoffman, Alice; Jeffrey, Mildred; Jones, Brownie Lee; Kemp, Maida Springer; Kennedy, Ola; Kimmel, Elizabeth; Kleiner, Lydia; Lucia, Carmen; Lunsford, Minnie; Lynch, Florence; Maietta, Julia; McElrath, Ah Quon; McGill, Eula; Merrill, Barbara; Meyerowitz, Ruth; Mount, Julia Luna; Neal, Arline; Neal, Fannie; Newman, Pauline; Nord, Elizabeth; Norwood, Rose; O'Farrell, Brigid; Palmquist, Rose; Peterson, Florence; Peurala, Alice; Pincus, Celia; Podojil, Antoinette; Reverby, Susan; Rikard, Marlene Hunt; Roberts, Geraldine; Roberts, Lillian; Robinson, Dolly Lowther; Roffman, Marion; Rostan, June; Schacht, John; Schwenkmeyer, Frieda; Scott, Glenn; Sullivan, Anna; Sweet, Gertrude; Tanzer, Shirley; Taylor, Pauline; Thornburgh, Lucille; Turner, Doris; Van Raaphorst, Donna; Ward, Angela Gizzi; Wertheimer, Barbara; Wiencek, Ruth; Wigderson, Seth; Bette Craig; Wilson, Becca; Wooding, Nelle; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO); American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME); American Federation of Teachers (AFT); American Labor Education Service (ALES); Brotherhood of Railway and Airline Clerks (BRAC); Cannery and Agricultural Workers Industrial Union (CAWIU); Communications Workers of America (CWA); Domestic Workers of America (DWA); Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union (HERE); Industrial Workers of the World (IWW); International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers; International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU); International Union of Electrical Workers (IU); National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees (NUHHCE) (1199); Office Workers Union (OWU); Philadelphia Federation of Teachers (PFT); Progressive Party; Service Employees International Union; Textile Workers Union of America; United Auto Workers (UWA); United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing and Allied Workers of America (UCAPAWA); United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers International Union; United Mine Workers of America (UMWA); United Rubber Workers (URW); United Steelworkers of America
7735919
- Sara Barron Interviewed by Barbara Wertheimer, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Mary Callahan Interviewed by Alice Hoffman, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  International Union of Electrical Workers (IU). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Sophie Cohen Interviewed by Deborah Shaffer and Carol Brightman, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Industrial Workers of the World (IWW).
- Catherine Conroy Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Communications Workers of America (CWA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Clara Day Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.
- Evelyn Dubrow Interviewed by Lydia Kleiner, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Mary Lawrance Elkuss Interviewed by Gloria Gordon, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA).
- Marie Fese Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Brotherhood of Railway and Airline Clerks (BRAC). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.
- Sara Fredgant Interviewed by Alice Hoffman, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Caroline Decker Gladstein Interviewed by Susan Cobble, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Cannery and Agricultural Workers Industrial Union (CAWIU). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.
- Dorothy Haener Interviewed by Lyn Goldfarb, Lydia Kliener, and Christine Miller, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  United Auto Workers (UWA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Lillian Herstein Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  American Federation of Teachers (AFT). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Mildred Jeffrey Interviewed by Ruth Meyerowitz, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Brownie Lee Jones Interviewed by Mary Frederickson, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  American Labor Education Service (ALES). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Maida Springer Kemp Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Maida Springer Kemp Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Ola Kennedy Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  United Steelworkers of America (USA). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.
- Elizabeth Kimmel Interviewed by Glenn Scott, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
- Carmen Lucia Interviewed by Seth Wigderson and Bette Craig, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  United Hatters, Cap and Millinery Workers International Union (UHCMW). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Minnie Lunsford Interviewed by June Rostan, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  United Mine Workers of America (UMWA). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Florence Lynch Interviewed by Debra Bernhardt, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  United Rubber Workers (URW).
- Julia Maietta Interviewed by Alice Hoffman, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Ah Quon McElrath Interviewed by Marion Roffman, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union (ILWU). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Eula McGill Interviewed by Jacquelyn Hall, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (ACWA). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Barbara Merrill Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU).
- Julia Luna Mount Interviewed by Becca Wilson, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing and Allied Workers of America (UCAPAWA). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.
- Arline Neal Interviewed by Lyn Goldfarb, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Service Employees' International Union (SEIU). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Fannie Neal Interviewed by Marlene Hunt Rikard, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Pauline Newman Interviewed by Barbara Wertheimer, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Elizabeth Nord Interviewed by James Findlay, Gary Julik, Christion Simmons, and Judy Smith, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Textile Workers' Union of America (TWUA). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.
- Rose Norwood Interviewed by Brigid O'Farrell, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW). This interview was marked restricted as of 1981.This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Rose Palmquist Interviewed by Mary Ellen Frank, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  International Brotherhood of Teamsters (IBT). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Florence Peterson Interviewed by Ruth Meyerowitz, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  United Auto Workes (UWA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Alice Peurala Interviewed by Elizabeth Balanoff, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  United Steelworkers of America (USA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Celia Pincus Interviewed by Alice Hoffman, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Philadelphia Federation of Teachers (PFT).
- Antoinette Podojil Interviewed by Lydia Kleiner, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Textile Workers' Union of America (TWUA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Geraldine Roberts Interviewed by Donna Van Raaphorst, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Domestic Workers of America (DWA). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Lillian Roberts Interviewed by Susan Reverby, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Dolly Lowther Robinson Interviewed by Bette Craig, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Frieda Schwenkmeyer Interviewed by Bette Craig, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Anna Sullivan Interviewed by Brigid O'Farrell, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Gertrude Sweet Interviewed by Shirley Tanzer, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Hotel and Restaurant Employees and Bartenders International Union (HERE). This interview is available in Catherwood Library on microfiche.
- Pauline Taylor Interviewed by Debra Bernhardt, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Progressive Party.
- Lucille Thornburgh Interviewed by June Rostan, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Doris Turner Interviewed by Cindia Cameron, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  National Union of Hospital and Health Care Employees (NUHHCE) (1199).
- Angela Gizzi Ward Interviewed by Susan Cobble, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Office Workers Union (OWU).
- Ruth Wiencek Interviewed by Carol Bowie, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Nelle Wooding Interviewed by John Schacht, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Communications Workers of America (CWA).
- Program on Women and Work, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Preliminary Sourcebook of Oral Histories of Trade Union and Working Women in the United States. Compiled by M. Brady Mikusko, Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations, University of Michigan-Wayne State University
- Black Women Oral History Project: Guide to the Transcripts, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Edited by Ruth Edmonds Hill and Patricia Miller King, The Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America, Radcliffe College